Originally, it was nighttime and idle.
Today, it's "gobo" and "idol.
I am Hisanori Yoshida, announcer of the Japan Broadcasting Corporation (NHK), and my name is Gobo.
This all started when Reni-chan Takagi first saw me and called me "gobo".
Personally, I am an announcer for Japan Broadcasting Corporation.
I used to wait for idols at NHK when I was in high school.
I've been an idol fan for almost 30 years now.
This may be one of the reasons why Stardust's idols and Japan Broadcasting System are getting closer these days.
I've been working with them on various projects, and the other day we held the Stapla Fest at the Yokohama Arena.
We had one representative from each group to participate in the festival, and we had a variety of competitions.
We had one representative from each group to compete in various events, such as kendama, dance, etc.
I called it "Geisha Fest" as a back theme, and each group had a number of people.
And each group had a number of members, and there were 10 competitions for people with nine wives or so.
So, I guess they all participate in one event or another.
Among them, there was one who showed great performance this time.
Kana Harimakana.
Yes, this one or that one?
I'm Kana Harima.
I wonder if it was too hard for you to do it.
I was wondering if it's okay to do it...
I thought, "No, what's the problem now?" "Even if I can't do it, I'll do it.
I'll do it.
You've never failed to get a result, have you? No.
That's right. I thought I'd give it a shot, so I did.
I had more than 40 idols on StarPlaza the other day.
Yes, more than 52 people, yes, a great number, and the one who stood out the most was Harima, thank you very much.
When this competition was announced, everyone was talking about it. I wonder what Halima will do.
That's right.
What did you think when you heard about this project, Mr. Harima?
Ah...
First of all, you said you were going to sing in a group competition.
I'm the only one, so what's going to happen? I wondered if I would be able to participate in the competition, since it would be so personal.
So I wondered if I would be able to get out.
I'm not a member of the cheerleading squad, but I tend to be treated that way. I wondered if I would be treated that way.
But this time, I was allowed to participate in the 10-lap event even though I was alone.
At first, I was quite happy to be allowed to participate.
Basically, you like to participate, don't you? I love it.
I'm not the type of person who is a mainstay at athletic events.
At the normal school level? I'm talking about the school level.
I can't even be a part of the relay.
I was the type of person who would stand alone in a large group of competitors and be happy.
I think I understand a little bit of what you're talking about.
Is that possible?
When it came time to play dodgeball with the class...
Then, you're on your own, and everyone else is on theirs, right? You don't do that, do you?
No.
What exactly did you have in mind now?
You know, a quarantine machine.
A quarantine machine?
Yes, there is.
Well, not necessarily.
It's the type of event where you only go out with a large group of people, like a quarantine machine.
It's the kind of event where you have one group and two groups.
When we do it with one group versus two groups...
What about you, Mr. Harima?
He was the type to participate in events where everyone participates together.
I was never the type to stand out.
I see. In relay races, when there are only four people in a class...
You were never chosen as a relay runner, were you?
Well, I was never chosen.
So I've never been in a situation where I had to cheer for everyone.
I've never participated in anything like that.
But this time, I was able to participate in all the events at the athletic meet.
I'm not a great all-rounder, but
I'm not a great all-rounder, but if you think of it in terms of athletic events
Decathlete
Yes, I was.
By the way, I said "decathlete.
I'm sure you know what "deCathlete" means.
I don't know, but...
Why did you put them together?
I don't know. I don't... I don't know. Decathlon?
Decalon?
Decalon.
That's that new medicine from Kobayashi, or something like that.
Decathlon?
Decathlon.
I don't know.
Decathlon
Someone was writing about it.
I wanted to be there, on Twitter.
So I thought, oh, that's how you say it, so I tried to match it
So, you know, something like...
You're not going to look it up?
No, I'm just wondering if it's already on Decathlon.
Oh, it's coming up?
Wait a minute.
Excuse me, are you in the early 1990s, Mr. Harima?
It's the year 2023.
It's still pre-Imode Japanese sensibilities.
I can look it up.
There are times when you have to look things up, right?
I didn't check only Decathlon.
You didn't check only Decathlon?
I've heard it said that it's the Decathlon.
I was wondering what it was...
I wonder if it's just a dialect. I was like...
Dialect?Dialect?
You haven't looked it up yet, have you?
When do you use the word "decathlon"?
Can you give me an example?
It's a word like "decathlon", so it's used like "deca-slone".
I thought...
What's a "dekaslon"?
It's like a decathlon, like a big loan.
Decathlon.
Sloan is important.
I mean, Sloan is like, dopey.
It's garbage.
I thought it was garbage.
What is it? What is it? Is it all there? Like he's just trying to keep it all together.
Like what's Sloane.
He thinks he's Sloane.
I thought there was a character like that somewhere in the world.
Somewhere out there.
I thought there was.
And he's in all ten of them.
That's how it is.
Is that how it is? That's how it is.
I was self-contained.
I was satisfied with that for now.
Especially when it came to the search, Mr. Decathlon, right?
That's what I thought.
You're close to me, aren't you, Mr. Decathlon?
I thought so.
Actually, you're not.
Really?
We have one in the Olympics.
The Decathlon?
Yes, the Decathlon.
In the games?
Yes, sir.
What kind of competition?
If you search for it, it'll come up.
They'll give you a guess what it's about.
But it's kind of like a triathlon.
Triathlon. I'm in the right place.
Triathlon?
If it's the same as triathlon, there's no reason to name it something else.
Is it like that?
What is a triathlon?
Well...
Running.
Running, running, running.
Swimming.
And one more thing.
It's like a snowboard.
You know, like a...
Right?
Like this.
Have you ever snowboarded, Mr. Hajime?
No, I haven't.
After that, you mean like this?
Do you know how snowboarding is like this?
A half pipe.
Yes, yes, that's it.
Why swim?
Why swim and run and then go to such a cold place? Like that.
That's what I thought.
The correct answer is a bicycle.
Bicycle.
That's what triathlons are for.
Triathlon doesn't have that.
Decathlon doesn't have that.
Decathlon is running, but not swimming.
What?
No swimming.
Running all the time?
All the time.
Well, maybe in the next marathon.
Like a 10,000-meter race.
Sure, sure.
I don't have a 10,000-meter run.
Maybe the 1,500-meter run.
Or the 100-meter dash.
Pole vaulting.
Discus throw...
There are all kinds of track and field events, right?
Yes, sir.
I'll do them all by myself.
What?
One day?
Well...
You said one day.
It might have been two days.
I think it took two days.
Oh, but it's hard work.
It's hard, isn't it?
It's exhausting.
What do you call this?
Decathlon!
That's it!
Oh!
Oh, so that's why I said Decathlon.Oh, so that's why I said Decathlon.
The time it took
Ah.
That's right.
It took you a long time.
It's not easy to do it all by yourself.
The others...
Webisodes only allow one person to participate in each event.
That's right.
Drawing, yelling, all that.
But you have to do everything by yourself.
Yes.
And I love Teshiro!
I love it.
At first I was really motivated.
I was like, "Okay, I'm going to do my best.
But when the time came for the show, he told me
I was told that there were tasks to be done
I started to learn more and more about the competition and what it's like.
As I learned more and more about the competition
I don't know what I should do by myself
I didn't know what I should do.
The day before the competition, I was quite anxious.
The day before the event, Yokohama Arena was already in
Yokohama Arena was already in Staffura Festival mode.
Everyone rehearsed at Yokohama Arena, didn't they?
Yes, we did.
And when we were rehearsing
To be honest, we were very nervous, weren't we?
Yes, I was.
It was terrible.
I was really nervous.
I don't know what to do.
I don't have an answer.
But you have to find the answer yourself.
That's what I'm saying.
I don't need anyone to tell me.
That's right.
I've never been to such an event before.
Because there is no right answer.
There's no right answer.
And you have to come up with your own answers.
I was like, "Well, I don't know what to do.
The day before was terrible.
From my point of view
In terms of the previous day...
Of course, I was on the initiating side.
I was at Yokohama Arena the day before.
I was at Yokohama Arena.
And when I went inside the arena
There's a big gymnasium.
Yes, there is.
A gymnasium.
It's about the same size as the stage.
We rehearse all kinds of things.
We play basketball and stuff.
Basically, the orcas seem to be having a lot of fun during the rehearsals, don't they?
Yes, yes, yes.
They're giving it their all.
Like, "Let's do it!
And then he comes out with a bang.
And then, if you look at his kneecaps like this...
Harima-san is doing this
Oh, no.
Hakuhan...
And he's doing it like this.
You know...
I'll say it again... our staff, like Mr. Nakade...
"What if Mr. Harima can't come out tomorrow?
to the point of saying, "What if Mr. Harima can't come out tomorrow?
That's right.
I wasn't really worried.
He was really worried about it.
Oh, my God.
I've never had an easy life as an idol, including when I was a member of 3B Junior.
It's never easy being an idol, is it?
Harima-san
But I was the most worried I've ever been.
You know...
No, Honey Rocket...
I said "honey rocket ausoro" to the Stapler festival
I've already participated in these three...
To borrow Takayanagi's expression
Solo and Tokyo Incidents
With Tortoise Matsumoto at Cohab.
I'm in the same league as Sheena Ringo.
Oh!
That's great, isn't it?
Sheena Ringo doesn't seem to be bothered by it.
No, I don't.
I feel like I'm going my own way.
Are you going your own way at the Staples Festival as a result?
I think I went my own way.
It's like, "Whatever will be, will be.
But until you get there...
It was pretty serious, wasn't it?
You cried, didn't you?You cried.
I couldn't get out of the bathroom.
Are you afraid to get out?
I don't know what to do.
If I left, I had to go.
To the rehearsal hall.
Like I said...
I've been inside StarPlaza...
I wonder if it'll be okay if we don't have a rehearsal.
Everyone was so worried.
But first of all, I was scared to leave the rehearsal.
I'm sure you guys are having fun.
I'm sure you're having fun, and I'm sure you're anxious, but
I thought that everyone would be able to do it.
I thought to myself
I was the only one who couldn't do it.
What should I do?
What if they think I'm just going to go out like that by myself?
I imagined all kinds of things.
What if they thought that I couldn't do it?
That's why I couldn't answer the door.
But you did.
I had to.
That's when I went from this knee-jerk mode to...
"Okay, let's go.
Was there a reason?
Or were you just not sure?
But when I went to the bathroom...
When I went to the bathroom.
When I went to the bathroom, the voice teacher forced me out.
Forced me out of the bathroom.
I don't think you should be in there.
But I was already out of there.
I had no choice but to go.
So I did.
It's out now.
You must be nervous inside.
I was like, "What am I going to do?
I might not be able to do anything.
I might be on my feet.
But now that I'm on the stage, I have no choice but to do it.
So we managed to get through the rehearsal.
So we managed to hold rehearsals, and when I performed...
The members of STAPLA and the staff around me were very encouraging.
They encouraged me and told me that I would be fine.
That was a big part of it.
Everyone was warm.
That's the difficult part, isn't it?
We were originally a group.
And for various reasons...
I made the decision to continue being an idol, but only one of us...
Now you're solo.
Subconsciously, you feel like you're not part of a team.
I don't know... it's like I don't have any team members.
It's been really hard for me.
Maybe that's true.
I really felt that when I was alone.
There is always a member next to you, isn't there?
When you're in a group...
When you are in a group, you are always there to help and support each other.
It was natural that we could support each other.
Suddenly it's not there anymore.
You have to do everything by yourself.
I had to think of everything by myself.
I was really anxious.
It's not easy being on your own.
Did you really feel it before that?
No, I didn't.
I thought it would be nice if I could do solo concerts
I thought it would be nice if I could do solo concerts by myself.
When I was in a group, I thought
I guess when you're in a group, it's like...
I don't know.
I mean, there's a certain amount of time that I can be in a group.
I'm the type of person who really wants to be in a group.
I guess that's true.
So there's a center.
And there is a leader.
And within that set of rules
I had to find the range where I could participate.
I wanted to be out more, but when I was on my own
But now that I'm on my own
I had no choice but to go out.
And when I had to manage to get help by myself
I felt how grateful I was to be a member of the band.
So the day before that day, I felt the weight of being a soloist for the first time.
I was almost crushed by the pressure.
I had no choice but to come out.
No, the whole staff is like teammates in a way.
I just felt like, "Oh, my God, I'm going to do it.
The show hasn't started yet.
That's right.
Well, Harima-san can go one more time.
I'll tell you about the show in the second half.